<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CNI on From 0.985mhz... to several Ghz</title>
    <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/categories/cni/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CNI on From 0.985mhz... to several Ghz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Myself</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 10:01:46 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.andreasm.io/categories/cni/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Securing Kubernetes clusters with Antrea Network Policies</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/06/21/securing-kubernetes-clusters-with-antrea-network-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 10:01:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/06/21/securing-kubernetes-clusters-with-antrea-network-policies/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I will go through how to utilize Antrea Network policies with Tanzu Mission Control and a little bit NSX. So jump in and hopefully get some ideas how what we can do with Antrea Network Policies and how to use them.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Antrea in vSphere with Tanzu</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/06/01/managing-antrea-in-vsphere-with-tanzu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 11:14:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/06/01/managing-antrea-in-vsphere-with-tanzu/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I will go through how to manage Antrea in a vSphere with Tanzu cluster using the Antrea CRD, and then explore some features and possibilites with Antrea
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antrea Egress</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/02/20/antrea-egress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 15:42:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/02/20/antrea-egress/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Antrea Egress: What is Egress when we talk about Kubernetes? Well if a pod wants to communicate to the outside world, outside the Kubernetes cluster it runs in, out of the worker node the pod resides on, this is egress traffic (definition &amp;quot;the action of going out of or leaving a place&amp;quot; and in network terminology means the direction is outward from itself).
Why does egress matter? Well, usually when the pods communicate out, they will use the IP address of the worker node they currently is deployed on.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSX Antrea Integration</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2022/10/11/nsx-antrea-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 21:38:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2022/10/11/nsx-antrea-integration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What is the NSX Antrea integration Assumptions: I assume that the reader is aware of what Antrea is, and what a CNI is and also what NSX is. If not head over here to read more on Antrea and here to read more on NSX.
For many years VMware NSX has help many customer secure their workload by using the NSX Distributed Firewall. As NSX has evolved over the years the different platform it supports has also broadened, from virtual machines, bare metal server, cloud workload and kubernetes pods.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antrea - Kubernetes CNI</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2021/07/10/antrea-kubernetes-cni/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2021/07/10/antrea-kubernetes-cni/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is an introduction post to Antrea, what it is and which features it has.
For more details head over to:
https://antrea.io/ and https://github.com/antrea-io/antrea
First of, Antrea is a CNI. CNI stands for Container Network Interface. As the world moves into Kubernetes more and more, we need a good CNI to support everything from network to security within Kubernetes. Thats where Antrea comes into play.
Antrea has a rich set of features such as:
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSX Advanced LoadBalancer with Antrea on Native K8s</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2020/10/08/nsx-advanced-loadbalancer-with-antrea-on-native-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2020/10/08/nsx-advanced-loadbalancer-with-antrea-on-native-k8s/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post will cover the steps to bring up a Kubernetes cluster in Ubuntu, then how to install and configure Antrea as CNI and how to install and configure NSX Advanced Load Balancer to use as a servicetype Load Balancer in the k8s environment with the use of Avi Kubernetes Operator.
Abbreviations used in this post:
NSX Advanced Load Balancer = NSX ALB Avi Kubernetes Operator = AKO Kubernetes = k8s Container Network Interface = CNI Load Balancer = lb Introduction to this post When working with pods in a k8s cluster there is often the use of nodePort, clusterIP and LoadBalancer.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
