<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on From 0.985mhz... to several Ghz</title>
    <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/categories/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on From 0.985mhz... to several Ghz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Myself</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 11:49:56 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.andreasm.io/categories/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Glance at Cilium CNI</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/12/18/a-quick-glance-at-cilium-cni/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 11:49:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/12/18/a-quick-glance-at-cilium-cni/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I will deploy Cilium in my k8s cluster and test some features and how it is to manage
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TKGi with NSX and NSX Advanced LoadBalancer</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/11/23/tkgi-with-nsx-and-nsx-advanced-loadbalancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 08:17:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/11/23/tkgi-with-nsx-and-nsx-advanced-loadbalancer/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I will go through installation of TKGi, using the EPMC installer, then how to configure TKGi to use NSX Advanced LoadBalancer
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tanzu Kubernetes Grid 2.2 &amp; Remote Workload Clusters</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/05/30/tanzu-kubernetes-grid-2.2-remote-workload-clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 14:54:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/05/30/tanzu-kubernetes-grid-2.2-remote-workload-clusters/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I will quickly go through how to use a Tanzu Kubernetes Grid management cluster to deploy and manage workload clusters in edge/remote locations.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere with Tanzu and Multi Zones part2</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/05/03/vsphere-with-tanzu-and-multi-zones-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 07:34:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/05/03/vsphere-with-tanzu-and-multi-zones-part2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I will quickly go through how we can use vSphere with Tanzu on three different vSphere clusters - Multi Zones for app placement.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere with Tanzu, Multi (three) Zones and NSX</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/05/03/vsphere-with-tanzu-multi-three-zones-and-nsx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 07:34:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/05/03/vsphere-with-tanzu-multi-three-zones-and-nsx/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post I will quickly go through how to deploy vSphere with Tanzu on three different vSphere clusters - Multi Zones
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tanzu with vSphere and different Tier-0s</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/04/14/tanzu-with-vsphere-and-different-tier-0s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 13:24:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/04/14/tanzu-with-vsphere-and-different-tier-0s/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post will take you trough how to configre Tanzu with vSphere using NSX with multiple Tier-0 and VRF Tier-0 gateways. It will also show you how to do this using DCLI and API
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antrea Egress</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/02/20/antrea-egress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 15:42:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2023/02/20/antrea-egress/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Antrea Egress: What is Egress when we talk about Kubernetes? Well if a pod wants to communicate to the outside world, outside the Kubernetes cluster it runs in, out of the worker node the pod resides on, this is egress traffic (definition &amp;quot;the action of going out of or leaving a place&amp;quot; and in network terminology means the direction is outward from itself).
Why does egress matter? Well, usually when the pods communicate out, they will use the IP address of the worker node they currently is deployed on.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 8 with Tanzu using NSX-T &amp; Avi LoadBalancer</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2022/10/26/vsphere-8-with-tanzu-using-nsx-t-avi-loadbalancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 12:03:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2022/10/26/vsphere-8-with-tanzu-using-nsx-t-avi-loadbalancer/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Deploy Tanzu in vSphere 8 with NSX and Avi Loadbalancer: This post will go through how to install Tanzu in vSphere 8 using NSX networking (including built in L4 loadbalancer) and Avi as L7 loadbalancer. The goal is to deploy Tanzu by using NSX for all networking needs, including the Kubernetes Api endpoint (L4) and utilize Avi as loadbalancer for all L7 (Ingress). The deployment of Tanzu with NSX is an automated process, but it does not include L7 loadbalancing.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSLB With AKO &amp; AMKO - NSX Advanced LoadBalancer</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2022/10/23/gslb-with-ako-amko-nsx-advanced-loadbalancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 08:22:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2022/10/23/gslb-with-ako-amko-nsx-advanced-loadbalancer/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Global Server LoadBalancing in VMware Tanzu with AMKO This post will go through how to configure AVI (NSX ALB) with GSLB in vSphere with Tanzu (TKGs) and an upstream k8s cluster in two different physical locations. I have already covered AKO in my previous posts, this post will assume knowledge of AKO (Avi Kubernetes Operator) and extend upon that with the use of AMKO (Avi Multi-Cluster Kubernetes Operator). The goal is to have the ability to scale my k8s applications between my &amp;quot;sites&amp;quot; and make them geo-redundant.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running the Unifi Controller in Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2022/10/23/running-the-unifi-controller-in-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 08:11:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2022/10/23/running-the-unifi-controller-in-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TOPICS: 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSX Antrea Integration</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2022/10/11/nsx-antrea-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 21:38:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2022/10/11/nsx-antrea-integration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What is the NSX Antrea integration Assumptions: I assume that the reader is aware of what Antrea is, and what a CNI is and also what NSX is. If not head over here to read more on Antrea and here to read more on NSX.
For many years VMware NSX has help many customer secure their workload by using the NSX Distributed Firewall. As NSX has evolved over the years the different platform it supports has also broadened, from virtual machines, bare metal server, cloud workload and kubernetes pods.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing your Antrea K8s clusters running in VMC from your on-prem NSX Manager</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2022/03/13/managing-your-antrea-k8s-clusters-running-in-vmc-from-your-on-prem-nsx-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2022/03/13/managing-your-antrea-k8s-clusters-running-in-vmc-from-your-on-prem-nsx-manager/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This week I was fortunate to get hold of a VMC on AWS environment and wanted to test out the possibility of managing my K8s security policies from my on-prem NSX manager by utilizing the integration of Antrea in NSX. I haven&#39;t covered that specific integration part in a blog yet, but in short: by using Antrea as your CNI and you are running NSX-T 3.2 you can manage all your K8s policies from the NSX manager GUI.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware NSX Application Platform</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2022/01/18/vmware-nsx-application-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2022/01/18/vmware-nsx-application-platform/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            VMware NSX 3.2 is out and packed with new features. One of them is the NSX Application Platform which runs on Kubernetes to provide the NSX ATP (Advanced Threat Protection) functionality such as NSX Intelligence (covered in a previous post), NSX Network Detection and Response (NDR) and NSX Malware. This post will go through how to spin up a K8s cluster for this specific scenario covering the pre-reqs from start to finish.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure NSX Advanced Load Balancer (NSX-ALB) as DNS provider</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2021/07/12/configure-nsx-advanced-load-balancer-nsx-alb-as-dns-provider/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2021/07/12/configure-nsx-advanced-load-balancer-nsx-alb-as-dns-provider/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            NSX ALB has a very useful feature built-in, to function as DNS server for your domains defined in your NSX-ALB environment. Meaning that all host-records will be automatically resolved by fqdn as soon as the service is created.
If you have followed my other post about how to configure the AKO (Avi Kubernetes Operator) here you are familiar with creating DNS profiles in NSX-ALB. The first step in configuring NSX-ALB as DNS provider is to configure one or more domain names in NSX-ALB.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K8s Ingress with NSX Advanced Load Balancer</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2021/07/11/k8s-ingress-with-nsx-advanced-load-balancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2021/07/11/k8s-ingress-with-nsx-advanced-load-balancer/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Abbreviations used in this article:
NSX Advanced Load Balancer = NSX-ALB K8s = Kubernetes (8 letters between the K and s in Kubernetes) SSL = Secure Sockets Layer AKO = Avi Kubernetes Operator (AVI now a VMware product called NSX Advanced Load Balancer) In one of my previous posts I wrote about how to install and configure AKO (Avi Kubernetes Operator) to use as Service type LoadBalancer.
This post will try to cover the basics of how to use NSX Advanced LoadBalancer by using AKO to handle our Ingress requests (ingress-controller).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antrea - Kubernetes CNI</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2021/07/10/antrea-kubernetes-cni/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2021/07/10/antrea-kubernetes-cni/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is an introduction post to Antrea, what it is and which features it has.
For more details head over to:
https://antrea.io/ and https://github.com/antrea-io/antrea
First of, Antrea is a CNI. CNI stands for Container Network Interface. As the world moves into Kubernetes more and more, we need a good CNI to support everything from network to security within Kubernetes. Thats where Antrea comes into play.
Antrea has a rich set of features such as:
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antrea Network Policies</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2021/07/10/antrea-network-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2021/07/10/antrea-network-policies/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post will go through the Antrea-native policy resources and how to use them to secure your Kubernetes environment combined with K8s network policies.
Abbreviations used in this article:
Container Network Interface = CNI Antrea Cluster Network Policies = ACNP Antrea Network Policies = ANP Kubernetes Network Policies = K8s policies or KNP When it comes to securing your K8s infrastructure it can be done in several layers in the infrastructure as a whole.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSX Advanced LoadBalancer with Antrea on Native K8s</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2020/10/08/nsx-advanced-loadbalancer-with-antrea-on-native-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2020/10/08/nsx-advanced-loadbalancer-with-antrea-on-native-k8s/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post will cover the steps to bring up a Kubernetes cluster in Ubuntu, then how to install and configure Antrea as CNI and how to install and configure NSX Advanced Load Balancer to use as a servicetype Load Balancer in the k8s environment with the use of Avi Kubernetes Operator.
Abbreviations used in this post:
NSX Advanced Load Balancer = NSX ALB Avi Kubernetes Operator = AKO Kubernetes = k8s Container Network Interface = CNI Load Balancer = lb Introduction to this post When working with pods in a k8s cluster there is often the use of nodePort, clusterIP and LoadBalancer.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy NSX-T 2.4 Edge Nodes on a N-VDS Logical Switch</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2019/03/09/deploy-nsx-t-2.4-edge-nodes-on-a-n-vds-logical-switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2019/03/09/deploy-nsx-t-2.4-edge-nodes-on-a-n-vds-logical-switch/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To be able to deploy an Edge node or nodes in your lab or other environment where you only have 2 physical nic you must be able to deploy it on a N-VDS switch as you have already migrated all your kernels etc to this one N-VDS switch.
But trying to do this from the NSX-T 2.4 manager GUI you will only have the option to deploy it to VSS or VDS portgroups, the N-VDS portgroups are not visible at all.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;General Error&#34; NSX-T Manager Firewall Section</title>
      <link>https://blog.andreasm.io/2018/09/05/general-error-nsx-t-manager-firewall-section/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andreasm.io/2018/09/05/general-error-nsx-t-manager-firewall-section/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you have missing objects in the firewall section before upgrading from NSX-T 2.1 to 2.2 you will experience a General Error in the GUI, on the Dashboard, and in the Firewall section of the GUI. You will even get general error when doing API calls to list the DFW sections https://NSXMGRIP/api/v1/firewall/sections: { &amp;quot;module\_name&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;common-services&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;error\_message&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;General error has occurred.&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;details&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;java.lang.NullPointerException&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;error\_code&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;100&amp;quot; }
If you have upgraded the fix is straight forward.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
